# Patrick Gerspach

72 4<sup>th</sup> Street, Garden City, NY 11530 (516) 238-7825 | pat.gerspach@gmail.com github.com/pgerspach | pgerspach.github.io/Portfolio-Main

#### Summary

My experience up to a few months ago was grounded in mechanical engineering, management, and consulting. However, my passion is for software and web development and I have been working tirelessly toward equipping myself with the proper knowledge to enter into this incredible digital world. I focus primarily on UX logic and back-end development, and have experience solving problems in multiple languages.

**Skills** 

HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Node.js, NoSQL, MySQL C, Java, Python, Git

**Education** University of Notre Dame

Notre Dame, IN May 2018

Mechanical Engineering

Certificate of Completion

Bachelor of Science

GPA: 3.60/4.00

Certifications

Columbia University Coding Boot Camp

New York, NY

March 2019

Average Grade: A

Professional Experience

WestRock Company, Deer Park, NY

June 2017 – Present

Engineering, Management Trainee

- Project lead on waste reduction initiative within a manufacturing plant
- Directed team members in individual assignments contributing to the successful execution of project goals
- Was promoted to lead man on a \$750,000 boiler replacement project, and saw it through from beginning to end
- Effectively and efficiently managed contractors and plant staff to ensure optimization of the project process

## MG Engineering D.P.C, New York, NY

May 2016 – July 2016

Mechanical Engineering Intern

- Drafted HVAC designs using AutoCAD in New York high-rise office floors
- Carefully surveyed job sites, including both demoed and partially demoed spaces, and took comprehensive notes to use in HVAC design

### ProMazo, South Bend, IN

February 2016 – May 2016

Technical Analysis Consultant

- Directed the technical analysis element of developing a consumer product for a Fortune 500 home appliances company
- Conducted experiments, compiled findings, and wrote a detailed memo making a professional recommendation regarding a technical component of the product

#### Leadership

Stanford Hall Basketball, Notre Dame, IN

May 2017 – May 2018

Team Captain

- Recruited for largest ever turnout at Stanford Hall basketball tryouts, and attained record fan attendance
- Reached playoffs for first time in team history